{
  "allQuestions": [
    {
      "resource": "Both Josh and Matt believe football has helped their health and mental wellbeing, and are among the 12 million people playing grassroots football in England. With over eight million of them being adults, we’ve sought to understand the social and economic value of the adult grassroots game, in which no-one is paid to play and no-one pays to watch. In what is the largest study of this type to date for a National Governing Body in the UK, we canvassed approximately 9000 participants to provide a nationally-representative sample that allows for robust statistical analysis.",
      "questionNumber": 1,
      "questionText": "Grassroots football results in no financial gain for any party involved",
      "answer": "Can't tell",
      "option1": "True",
      "option2": "False",
      "option3": "Can't tell",
      "option4": ""
    },
    {
      "resource": "Both Josh and Matt believe football has helped their health and mental wellbeing, and are among the 12 million people playing grassroots football in England. With over eight million of them being adults, we’ve sought to understand the social and economic value of the adult grassroots game, in which no-one is paid to play and no-one pays to watch. In what is the largest study of this type to date for a National Governing Body in the UK, we canvassed approximately 9000 participants to provide a nationally-representative sample that allows for robust statistical analysis.",
      "questionNumber": 2,
      "questionText": "The most amount of people surveyed for a study performed by a national governing body is 9000",
      "answer": "True",
      "option1": "True",
      "option2": "False",
      "option3": "Can't tell",
      "option4": ""
    },
    {
      "resource": "Both Josh and Matt believe football has helped their health and mental wellbeing, and are among the 12 million people playing grassroots football in England. With over eight million of them being adults, we’ve sought to understand the social and economic value of the adult grassroots game, in which no-one is paid to play and no-one pays to watch. In what is the largest study of this type to date for a National Governing Body in the UK, we canvassed approximately 9000 participants to provide a nationally-representative sample that allows for robust statistical analysis.",
      "questionNumber": 3,
      "questionText": "Less than two thirds of grassroot footballers are adults",
      "answer": "False",
      "option1": "True",
      "option2": "False",
      "option3": "Can't tell",
      "option4": ""
    },
    {
      "resource": "Both Josh and Matt believe football has helped their health and mental wellbeing, and are among the 12 million people playing grassroots football in England. With over eight million of them being adults, we’ve sought to understand the social and economic value of the adult grassroots game, in which no-one is paid to play and no-one pays to watch. In what is the largest study of this type to date for a National Governing Body in the UK, we canvassed approximately 9000 participants to provide a nationally-representative sample that allows for robust statistical analysis.",
      "questionNumber": 4,
      "questionText": "There is a social benefit to playing grassroots football",
      "answer": "Can't tell",
      "option1": "True",
      "option2": "False",
      "option3": "Can't tell",
      "option4": ""
    },
    {
      "resource": "A new study found that people who drank more than 1 sugar-sweetened drink each day were likely to see levels of fats in their blood change for the worse. While that can raise the risk of a heart attack and stroke, it does not mean that fizzy drinks directly cause heart attacks.\n\nResearchers looked at the diets of 6,370 middle-aged adults in the US. They followed them over a minimum of 4 years and maximum 23 years. People had blood tests every 4 years to measure cholesterol and triglycerides (a type of fat that can block arteries)",
      "questionNumber": 5,
      "questionText": "Which statement is best supported by the body of text:",
      "answer": "Drinking fizzy drinks that have sugar can contribute towards having a heart attack",
      "option1": "Adults in the US are more likely to have a heart problem",
      "option2": "Having 1 sugar-sweetened drink each day is not bad for you",
      "option3": "Drinking fizzy drinks that have sugar can contribute towards having a heart attack",
      "option4": "Blood tests are the best way to measure the health of your heart"
    },
    {
      "resource": "A new study found that people who drank more than 1 sugar-sweetened drink each day were likely to see levels of fats in their blood change for the worse. While that can raise the risk of a heart attack and stroke, it does not mean that fizzy drinks directly cause heart attacks.\n\nResearchers looked at the diets of 6,370 middle-aged adults in the US. They followed them over a minimum of 4 years and maximum 23 years. People had blood tests every 4 years to measure cholesterol and triglycerides (a type of fat that can block arteries)",
      "questionNumber": 6,
      "questionText": "It can be concluded from the body of text that the author:",
      "answer": "Has no particular bias in this instance",
      "option1": "Is against you drinking fizzy drinks",
      "option2": "Has no particular bias in this instance",
      "option3": "Is a researcher",
      "option4": "Is based in the US"
    },
    {
      "resource": "A new study found that people who drank more than 1 sugar-sweetened drink each day were likely to see levels of fats in their blood change for the worse. While that can raise the risk of a heart attack and stroke, it does not mean that fizzy drinks directly cause heart attacks.\n\nResearchers looked at the diets of 6,370 middle-aged adults in the US. They followed them over a minimum of 4 years and maximum 23 years. People had blood tests every 4 years to measure cholesterol and triglycerides (a type of fat that can block arteries)",
      "questionNumber": 7,
      "questionText": "Which statement is least likely to be true?",
      "answer": "The researchers followed participants for an average of 13.5 years",
      "option1": "Drinking multiple fizzy drinks a day can lead to heart problems",
      "option2": "The researchers followed participants for an average of 13.5 years",
      "option3": "Having more than one sugar sweetened drink impacted levels of fat in the heart",
      "option4": "There have been previous studies on this topic"
    },
    {
      "resource": "A new study found that people who drank more than 1 sugar-sweetened drink each day were likely to see levels of fats in their blood change for the worse. While that can raise the risk of a heart attack and stroke, it does not mean that fizzy drinks directly cause heart attacks.\n\nResearchers looked at the diets of 6,370 middle-aged adults in the US. They followed them over a minimum of 4 years and maximum 23 years. People had blood tests every 4 years to measure cholesterol and triglycerides (a type of fat that can block arteries)",
      "questionNumber": 8,
      "questionText": "'For the worse' as mentioned in the context of the text is most likely to mean:",
      "answer": "Increase in the levels of fat in the blood",
      "option1": "Worse types of fat in the blood",
      "option2": "Higher peaks and troughs of levels of fat",
      "option3": "Decrease of levels of fat in the blood",
      "option4": "Increase in the levels of fat in the blood"
    },
    {
      "resource": "The internet traces its origins to the ARPAnet, created by the US Defence Department’s Advanced Research Projects Agency in the 1960s. Many other networks were developed - some by commercial companies, some in different countries - but they couldn’t easily talk to one another.\n\nVint Cerf and Bob Kahn developed TCP/IP, ’A Protocol for Packet Network Interconnection’ (in 1974), to connect different networks. The internet was thus a ’network of networks’, although the Internet Protocol (IP) came to dominate networking.\n\nAt the end of 1969, there were only four computers on ARPAnet, and they were all at US universities. This grew to 5,000 internet hosts in 1986, after which the number of users grew rapidly into the millions and then hundreds of millions",
      "questionNumber": 9,
      "questionText": "One of the problems the internet had in its early years was",
      "answer": "It wasn’t easy for it to talk to other networks",
      "option1": "It was created by the US Defence Department",
      "option2": "It wasn’t easy for it to talk to other networks",
      "option3": "It wasn’t created for commercial purposes",
      "option4": "There were only four computers that supported it"
    },
    {
      "resource": "The internet traces its origins to the ARPAnet, created by the US Defence Department’s Advanced Research Projects Agency in the 1960s. Many other networks were developed - some by commercial companies, some in different countries - but they couldn’t easily talk to one another.\n\nVint Cerf and Bob Kahn developed TCP/IP, ’A Protocol for Packet Network Interconnection’ (in 1974), to connect different networks. The internet was thus a ’network of networks’, although the Internet Protocol (IP) came to dominate networking.\n\nAt the end of 1969, there were only four computers on ARPAnet, and they were all at US universities. This grew to 5,000 internet hosts in 1986, after which the number of users grew rapidly into the millions and then hundreds of millions",
      "questionNumber": 10,
      "questionText": "From the text, one can infer that: ",
      "answer": "The Development of TCP/IP helped to spread the use of the internet",
      "option1": "Commercial companies developed different networks using ARPAnet as a model",
      "option2": "Vint Cerf and Bob Kahn worked for the US Defence Department",
      "option3": "The Development of TCP/IP helped to spread the use of the internet",
      "option4": "The internet was neither useful nor popular prior to 1986"
    },
    {
      "resource": "The internet traces its origins to the ARPAnet, created by the US Defence Department’s Advanced Research Projects Agency in the 1960s. Many other networks were developed - some by commercial companies, some in different countries - but they couldn’t easily talk to one another.\n\nVint Cerf and Bob Kahn developed TCP/IP, ’A Protocol for Packet Network Interconnection’ (in 1974), to connect different networks. The internet was thus a ’network of networks’, although the Internet Protocol (IP) came to dominate networking.\n\nAt the end of 1969, there were only four computers on ARPAnet, and they were all at US universities. This grew to 5,000 internet hosts in 1986, after which the number of users grew rapidly into the millions and then hundreds of millions",
      "questionNumber": 11,
      "questionText": "The passage claims that the internet we use today:",
      "answer": "Comes from America",
      "option1": "Comes from America",
      "option2": "Could’ve come from another country ",
      "option3": "Was only capable of being used in America during the 1960’s",
      "option4": "Had its origins in commercial development"
    },
    {
      "resource": "The internet traces its origins to the ARPAnet, created by the US Defence Department’s Advanced Research Projects Agency in the 1960s. Many other networks were developed - some by commercial companies, some in different countries - but they couldn’t easily talk to one another.\n\nVint Cerf and Bob Kahn developed TCP/IP, ’A Protocol for Packet Network Interconnection’ (in 1974), to connect different networks. The internet was thus a ’network of networks’, although the Internet Protocol (IP) came to dominate networking.\n\nAt the end of 1969, there were only four computers on ARPAnet, and they were all at US universities. This grew to 5,000 internet hosts in 1986, after which the number of users grew rapidly into the millions and then hundreds of millions",
      "questionNumber": 12,
      "questionText": "Which of the following statements is true:",
      "answer": "The first rendition of the internet was developed and used in the 1960’s",
      "option1": "The first rendition of the internet was developed and used in the 1960’s",
      "option2": "The 1970’s was when the internet became usable",
      "option3": "Between the 1960’s and the 1980’s was the time period which most people started using the internet",
      "option4": "Only an American could use the internet up until the creation of the TCP/IP"
    },
    {
      "resource": "By far the most popular explanation of lift is Bernoulli’s theorem, a principle identified by Swiss mathematician Daniel Bernoulli in his 1738 treatise, Hydrodynamica. Bernoulli came from a family of mathematicians. His father, Johann, made contributions to the calculus, and his Uncle Jakob coined the term “integral.” Many of Daniel Bernoulli’s contributions had to do with fluid flow: Air is a fluid, and the theorem associated with his name is commonly expressed in terms of fluid dynamics. Stated simply, Bernoulli’s law says that the pressure of a fluid decreases as its velocity increases, and vice versa. \n\nBernoulli’s theorem attempts to explain lift as a consequence of the curved upper surface of an airfoil, the technical name for an airplane wing. Because of this curvature, the idea goes, air traveling across the top of the wing moves faster than the air moving along the wing’s bottom surface, which is flat. Bernoulli’s theorem says that the increased speed atop the wing is associated with a region of lower pressure there, which is lift",
      "questionNumber": 13,
      "questionText": "The Bernoulli family: ",
      "answer": "Had made contributions to academia in different fields",
      "option1": "Had made contributions to theories of ‘lift’ prior to Daniel",
      "option2": "Jointly contributed towards the treatise, Hydrodynamica",
      "option3": "Had made no academic contributions prior to Daniel",
      "option4": "Had made contributions to academia in different fields"
    },
    {
      "resource": "By far the most popular explanation of lift is Bernoulli’s theorem, a principle identified by Swiss mathematician Daniel Bernoulli in his 1738 treatise, Hydrodynamica. Bernoulli came from a family of mathematicians. His father, Johann, made contributions to the calculus, and his Uncle Jakob coined the term “integral.” Many of Daniel Bernoulli’s contributions had to do with fluid flow: Air is a fluid, and the theorem associated with his name is commonly expressed in terms of fluid dynamics. Stated simply, Bernoulli’s law says that the pressure of a fluid decreases as its velocity increases, and vice versa. \n\nBernoulli’s theorem attempts to explain lift as a consequence of the curved upper surface of an airfoil, the technical name for an airplane wing. Because of this curvature, the idea goes, air traveling across the top of the wing moves faster than the air moving along the wing’s bottom surface, which is flat. Bernoulli’s theorem says that the increased speed atop the wing is associated with a region of lower pressure there, which is lift",
      "questionNumber": 14,
      "questionText": "Bernoulli’s law describes:",
      "answer": "There’s an inverse relationship between the pressure of a fluid and it’s velocity",
      "option1": "An increase in pressure of a fluid results in an equal increase in the velocity",
      "option2": "Decreasing the velocity of a fluid does not necessarily result in a fall of it’s pressure",
      "option3": "There’s an inverse relationship between the pressure of a fluid and it’s velocity",
      "option4": "If a fluid moves faster, it will cause objects to lift"
    },
    {
      "resource": "By far the most popular explanation of lift is Bernoulli’s theorem, a principle identified by Swiss mathematician Daniel Bernoulli in his 1738 treatise, Hydrodynamica. Bernoulli came from a family of mathematicians. His father, Johann, made contributions to the calculus, and his Uncle Jakob coined the term “integral.” Many of Daniel Bernoulli’s contributions had to do with fluid flow: Air is a fluid, and the theorem associated with his name is commonly expressed in terms of fluid dynamics. Stated simply, Bernoulli’s law says that the pressure of a fluid decreases as its velocity increases, and vice versa. \n\nBernoulli’s theorem attempts to explain lift as a consequence of the curved upper surface of an airfoil, the technical name for an airplane wing. Because of this curvature, the idea goes, air traveling across the top of the wing moves faster than the air moving along the wing’s bottom surface, which is flat. Bernoulli’s theorem says that the increased speed atop the wing is associated with a region of lower pressure there, which is lift",
      "questionNumber": 15,
      "questionText": "Which of the following statements is true according to the text:",
      "answer": "The higher speed on top of an aeroplane wing is owed to the decreased amount of pressure",
      "option1": "In order for an object to lift, there must be a curved surface involved",
      "option2": "Air travelling across the top of the wing must move faster than the air below the wing, in order for lift",
      "option3": "The higher speed on top of an aeroplane wing is owed to the decreased amount of pressure",
      "option4": "All of Daniel Bernoulli’s academic contributions have been to do with fluid flow"
    },
    {
      "resource": "By far the most popular explanation of lift is Bernoulli’s theorem, a principle identified by Swiss mathematician Daniel Bernoulli in his 1738 treatise, Hydrodynamica. Bernoulli came from a family of mathematicians. His father, Johann, made contributions to the calculus, and his Uncle Jakob coined the term “integral.” Many of Daniel Bernoulli’s contributions had to do with fluid flow: Air is a fluid, and the theorem associated with his name is commonly expressed in terms of fluid dynamics. Stated simply, Bernoulli’s law says that the pressure of a fluid decreases as its velocity increases, and vice versa. \n\nBernoulli’s theorem attempts to explain lift as a consequence of the curved upper surface of an airfoil, the technical name for an airplane wing. Because of this curvature, the idea goes, air traveling across the top of the wing moves faster than the air moving along the wing’s bottom surface, which is flat. Bernoulli’s theorem says that the increased speed atop the wing is associated with a region of lower pressure there, which is lift",
      "questionNumber": 16,
      "questionText": "What causes aeroplanes to take off?",
      "answer": "Air travelling across the top of the wing, being quicker than the air moving along the wing’s bottom surface",
      "option1": "Air travelling across the top of the wing, being quicker than the air moving along the wing’s bottom surface",
      "option2": "The curvature of the airfoil",
      "option3": "The speed of the air pushing against the floor",
      "option4": "The engines"
    },
    {
      "resource": "When we lose rainforests, we lose an important natural resource. Tropical rainforests are centers of biodiversity, holding an estimated half of the world’s plants and animals, many of which have yet to be catalogued (some scientists estimate that it’s two-thirds of the world's plants). Rainforests produce, store, and filter water, protecting against soil erosion, floods, and drought.\n\nMany of the plants found in rainforests are being used to make medicine, including anti-cancer drugs, along with beauty products and foods. One drug under development for treating HIV, Calanolide A, is derived from a tree discovered on Malaysian Borneo. And Brazil nut trees refuse to grow anywhere but in undisturbed sections of the Amazon rainforest. There, the trees are pollinated by bees that also visit orchids, and their seeds are spread by agoutis, small tree mammals. Rainforests are also home to endangered or protected animals such as the Sumatran rhino, orangutans, and jaguars.",
      "questionNumber": 17,
      "questionText": "Based on the article it can be inferred that:",
      "answer": "Without rainforests there would be more floods and drought",
      "option1": "There are more animals and plants in the rainforest that can be discovered",
      "option2": "The plants in the rainforest have healing properties",
      "option3": "Without rainforests there would be more floods and drought",
      "option4": "All animals in the rainforest are either endangered or protected"
    },
    {
      "resource": "When we lose rainforests, we lose an important natural resource. Tropical rainforests are centers of biodiversity, holding an estimated half of the world’s plants and animals, many of which have yet to be catalogued (some scientists estimate that it’s two-thirds of the world's plants). Rainforests produce, store, and filter water, protecting against soil erosion, floods, and drought.\n\nMany of the plants found in rainforests are being used to make medicine, including anti-cancer drugs, along with beauty products and foods. One drug under development for treating HIV, Calanolide A, is derived from a tree discovered on Malaysian Borneo. And Brazil nut trees refuse to grow anywhere but in undisturbed sections of the Amazon rainforest. There, the trees are pollinated by bees that also visit orchids, and their seeds are spread by agoutis, small tree mammals. Rainforests are also home to endangered or protected animals such as the Sumatran rhino, orangutans, and jaguars.",
      "questionNumber": 18,
      "questionText": "According to the article:",
      "answer": "Rainforests are the home to one in two of the world’s animals and plants",
      "option1": "Rainforests don’t just store water, they also consume it",
      "option2": "Rainforests produce natural medicines",
      "option3": "Rainforests are the home to one in two of the world’s animals and plants",
      "option4": "Brazil nut trees can only grow in rainforest conditions"
    },
    {
      "resource": "When we lose rainforests, we lose an important natural resource. Tropical rainforests are centers of biodiversity, holding an estimated half of the world’s plants and animals, many of which have yet to be catalogued (some scientists estimate that it’s two-thirds of the world's plants). Rainforests produce, store, and filter water, protecting against soil erosion, floods, and drought.\n\nMany of the plants found in rainforests are being used to make medicine, including anti-cancer drugs, along with beauty products and foods. One drug under development for treating HIV, Calanolide A, is derived from a tree discovered on Malaysian Borneo. And Brazil nut trees refuse to grow anywhere but in undisturbed sections of the Amazon rainforest. There, the trees are pollinated by bees that also visit orchids, and their seeds are spread by agoutis, small tree mammals. Rainforests are also home to endangered or protected animals such as the Sumatran rhino, orangutans, and jaguars.",
      "questionNumber": 19,
      "questionText": "Which of the following statements are false:",
      "answer": "The rainforest does not contribute towards the beauty industry",
      "option1": "Calanolide A comes from the Malaysian Borneo",
      "option2": "Brazil nut trees grow in population thanks to the animals of the rainforest",
      "option3": "Jaguars are neither protected nor endangered",
      "option4": "The rainforest does not contribute towards the beauty industry"
    },
    {
      "resource": "When we lose rainforests, we lose an important natural resource. Tropical rainforests are centers of biodiversity, holding an estimated half of the world’s plants and animals, many of which have yet to be catalogued (some scientists estimate that it’s two-thirds of the world's plants). Rainforests produce, store, and filter water, protecting against soil erosion, floods, and drought.\n\nMany of the plants found in rainforests are being used to make medicine, including anti-cancer drugs, along with beauty products and foods. One drug under development for treating HIV, Calanolide A, is derived from a tree discovered on Malaysian Borneo. And Brazil nut trees refuse to grow anywhere but in undisturbed sections of the Amazon rainforest. There, the trees are pollinated by bees that also visit orchids, and their seeds are spread by agoutis, small tree mammals. Rainforests are also home to endangered or protected animals such as the Sumatran rhino, orangutans, and jaguars.",
      "questionNumber": 20,
      "questionText": "Tropical rainforests definitely hold:",
      "answer": "Tropical rainforests definitely",
      "option1": "Air travelling across the top of the wing, being quicker than the air moving along the wing’s bottom surface",
      "option2": "The curvature of the airfoil",
      "option3": "The speed of the air pushing against the floor",
      "option4": "The engines"
    },
    {
      "resource": "A free trade agreement (FTA) is defined by the World Trade Organisation as an agreement between countries that removes tariffs and other restrictions on “substantially all” goods traded between them. These agreements differ from customs unions in that countries remove tariffs on goods traded between them but do not adopt the same tariffs on goods imported from other countries. FTAs require complex rules that define whether a good produced in one FTA partner is eligible for tariff-free treatment in another. These “rules of origin” prevent valuable parts such as engines and high-tech components that are made outside an FTA from being slipped into a high external tariff FTA partner from a low external tariff FTA partner. Modern FTAs sometimes remove barriers for trading services and the sectors covered vary according to the economic relationships between the countries involved",
      "questionNumber": 21,
      "questionText": " A free trade agreement is defined as:",
      "answer": "The removal of all restrictions between a set of countries to allow nearly all goods to be traded between them",
      "option1": "The removal of all restrictions between a set of countries to allow nearly all goods to be traded between them",
      "option2": "The removal of tariffs and other blockers on nearly all goods and services traded between two countries",
      "option3": "An agreement between countries regarding which goods may be accessible as part of a trade agreement",
      "option4": "The removal of all tariffs on substantially all goods traded between two countries"
    },
    {
      "resource": "A free trade agreement (FTA) is defined by the World Trade Organisation as an agreement between countries that removes tariffs and other restrictions on “substantially all” goods traded between them. These agreements differ from customs unions in that countries remove tariffs on goods traded between them but do not adopt the same tariffs on goods imported from other countries. FTAs require complex rules that define whether a good produced in one FTA partner is eligible for tariff-free treatment in another. These “rules of origin” prevent valuable parts such as engines and high-tech components that are made outside an FTA from being slipped into a high external tariff FTA partner from a low external tariff FTA partner. Modern FTAs sometimes remove barriers for trading services and the sectors covered vary according to the economic relationships between the countries involved",
      "questionNumber": 22,
      "questionText": "What is the difference between modern and traditional FTAs:",
      "answer": "Services can also be traded under FTAs",
      "option1": "The type of FTA used depends on the countries involved",
      "option2": "Modern FTAs focus on specific sectors, Traditional FTAs range over many different parts of the economy",
      "option3": "Economic relationships influence modern FTAs but have little to do with more traditional FTAs ",
      "option4": "Services can also be traded under FTAs"
    },
    {
      "resource": "A free trade agreement (FTA) is defined by the World Trade Organisation as an agreement between countries that removes tariffs and other restrictions on “substantially all” goods traded between them. These agreements differ from customs unions in that countries remove tariffs on goods traded between them but do not adopt the same tariffs on goods imported from other countries. FTAs require complex rules that define whether a good produced in one FTA partner is eligible for tariff-free treatment in another. These “rules of origin” prevent valuable parts such as engines and high-tech components that are made outside an FTA from being slipped into a high external tariff FTA partner from a low external tariff FTA partner. Modern FTAs sometimes remove barriers for trading services and the sectors covered vary according to the economic relationships between the countries involved",
      "questionNumber": 23,
      "questionText": "What is the difference between a FTA and a customs union:",
      "answer": "Customs unions impose common external tariffs on external parties",
      "option1": "FTAs remove all tariffs between countries, customs union do not",
      "option2": "FTAs are between two countries, FTAs can include any number of countries",
      "option3": "Customs unions impose common external tariffs on external parties",
      "option4": "Customs unions set the same tariffs for countries outside the agreement"
    },
    {
      "resource": "A free trade agreement (FTA) is defined by the World Trade Organisation as an agreement between countries that removes tariffs and other restrictions on “substantially all” goods traded between them. These agreements differ from customs unions in that countries remove tariffs on goods traded between them but do not adopt the same tariffs on goods imported from other countries. FTAs require complex rules that define whether a good produced in one FTA partner is eligible for tariff-free treatment in another. These “rules of origin” prevent valuable parts such as engines and high-tech components that are made outside an FTA from being slipped into a high external tariff FTA partner from a low external tariff FTA partner. Modern FTAs sometimes remove barriers for trading services and the sectors covered vary according to the economic relationships between the countries involved",
      "questionNumber": 24,
      "questionText": "Rules of origin are made in order to avoid:",
      "answer": "Prevent objects ending up in high external tariff FTA partners, coming from low external tariff FTA partners",
      "option1": "Objects moving from a high external tariff FTA partner to a low external tariff FTA partner",
      "option2": "Prevent high-value goods being made outside an FTA and being traded in",
      "option3": "High value objects moving from an area with a FTA in place to an area without one",
      "option4": "Prevent objects ending up in high external tariff FTA partners, coming from low external tariff FTA partners"
    },
    {
      "resource": "Treating the symptoms and supporting your immune system is the best first course of action to get you feeling better faster. Everyone’s experience of a cold is slightly different from the next person’s, and there are so many options in the cold and flu aisle at the drugstore. How do you know which symptom remedies are right for you? \n\nThe key is to find what works best for you personally, for your symptoms, whether it’s over-the-counter cold and flu remedies or soothing herbal tea. If, for example, you experience bad sinus pressure when you have an upper respiratory infection, a decongestant like pseudoephedrine or a nasal sinus rinse might be good to have on hand. If it’s coughing that usually makes your life miserable during a head or chest cold, you could try inhaling hot steam from the sink or shower a few times a day to help break things up. \n\nYour immune system’s job is to eradicate viral and bacterial infections from your body. It’s very effective as long as you provide it with the proper support. The best way to do that is to rest. Being stressed out or not getting enough sleep releases hormones that suppress your immune system",
      "questionNumber": 25,
      "questionText": "The best thing to do as soon as you get ill is:",
      "answer": "Treat your symptoms",
      "option1": "Treat your symptoms",
      "option2": "Go to bed and rest",
      "option3": "Speak to a doctor",
      "option4": "Visit the drugstore and find the remedy"
    },
    {
      "resource": "Treating the symptoms and supporting your immune system is the best first course of action to get you feeling better faster. Everyone’s experience of a cold is slightly different from the next person’s, and there are so many options in the cold and flu aisle at the drugstore. How do you know which symptom remedies are right for you? \n\nThe key is to find what works best for you personally, for your symptoms, whether it’s over-the-counter cold and flu remedies or soothing herbal tea. If, for example, you experience bad sinus pressure when you have an upper respiratory infection, a decongestant like pseudoephedrine or a nasal sinus rinse might be good to have on hand. If it’s coughing that usually makes your life miserable during a head or chest cold, you could try inhaling hot steam from the sink or shower a few times a day to help break things up. \n\nYour immune system’s job is to eradicate viral and bacterial infections from your body. It’s very effective as long as you provide it with the proper support. The best way to do that is to rest. Being stressed out or not getting enough sleep releases hormones that suppress your immune system",
      "questionNumber": 26,
      "questionText": "What can be inferred from the text:",
      "answer": "The cold can affect people differently",
      "option1": "There are different remedies available for different illnesses",
      "option2": "The cold can affect people differently",
      "option3": "A weak immune system may mean you need help fighting off a cold",
      "option4": "How you feel is the biggest factor in getting rid of an illness"
    },
    {
      "resource": "Treating the symptoms and supporting your immune system is the best first course of action to get you feeling better faster. Everyone’s experience of a cold is slightly different from the next person’s, and there are so many options in the cold and flu aisle at the drugstore. How do you know which symptom remedies are right for you? \n\nThe key is to find what works best for you personally, for your symptoms, whether it’s over-the-counter cold and flu remedies or soothing herbal tea. If, for example, you experience bad sinus pressure when you have an upper respiratory infection, a decongestant like pseudoephedrine or a nasal sinus rinse might be good to have on hand. If it’s coughing that usually makes your life miserable during a head or chest cold, you could try inhaling hot steam from the sink or shower a few times a day to help break things up. \n\nYour immune system’s job is to eradicate viral and bacterial infections from your body. It’s very effective as long as you provide it with the proper support. The best way to do that is to rest. Being stressed out or not getting enough sleep releases hormones that suppress your immune system",
      "questionNumber": 27,
      "questionText": "What are the two illnesses referenced in the text:",
      "answer": "Upper respiratory infection and head or chest cold",
      "option1": "Cold and flu",
      "option2": "Viral and bacterial infections",
      "option3": "Flu and infections",
      "option4": "Upper respiratory infection and head or chest cold"
    },
    {
      "resource": "Treating the symptoms and supporting your immune system is the best first course of action to get you feeling better faster. Everyone’s experience of a cold is slightly different from the next person’s, and there are so many options in the cold and flu aisle at the drugstore. How do you know which symptom remedies are right for you? \n\nThe key is to find what works best for you personally, for your symptoms, whether it’s over-the-counter cold and flu remedies or soothing herbal tea. If, for example, you experience bad sinus pressure when you have an upper respiratory infection, a decongestant like pseudoephedrine or a nasal sinus rinse might be good to have on hand. If it’s coughing that usually makes your life miserable during a head or chest cold, you could try inhaling hot steam from the sink or shower a few times a day to help break things up. \n\nYour immune system’s job is to eradicate viral and bacterial infections from your body. It’s very effective as long as you provide it with the proper support. The best way to do that is to rest. Being stressed out or not getting enough sleep releases hormones that suppress your immune system",
      "questionNumber": 28,
      "questionText": "The best way to help your immune system is:",
      "answer": "Rest",
      "option1": "Take the relevant treatments",
      "option2": "Don’t get stressed out",
      "option3": "Get medicine from the store",
      "option4": "Rest"
    },
    {
      "resource": "The classically trained Édouard Manet (1832–1883) straddled Realism and Impressionism. He influenced the Impressionists and was, in turn, influenced by them. In the 1860s, the Impressionists began meeting near Manet’s studio at Café Guerbois. He was the unofficial head of the twice-weekly meetings, which included Monet, Renoir, Degas, Alfred Sisley, Émile Zola, and sometimes Paul Cézanne, Camille Pissarro, and others. \n\nWhat was the bridge between Realism and Impressionism? It was Manet’s new approach to painting, his innovations with color and brushwork. \n\nEarlier artists began painting their canvases with a layer of dark, usually brown, paint and then built layers of paint on top of it. Of course, they had to wait for each layer to dry before adding the next one. Finally, they glazed the painting to give the surface a smooth finish. This process could take weeks or months. Obviously, the models couldn’t pose all that time, so painters frequently added layers without the model present.\n\nAs a Realist, Manet preferred to paint from life — in other words, with his model in front of him. He did this by completing his paintings in one sitting. How did he achieve this high-speed efficiency? By not painting in layers and not glazing the final product. That meant he had to choose the perfect color right off the bat because there were no layers to fall back on. When he made a mistake, he scraped off the paint, down to the bare canvas, and then repainted that area.",
      "questionNumber": 29,
      "questionText": "Manet layered and glazed his paintings in one sitting?",
      "answer": "False",
      "option1": "True",
      "option2": "False",
      "option3": "",
      "option4": ""
    },
    {
      "resource": "The classically trained Édouard Manet (1832–1883) straddled Realism and Impressionism. He influenced the Impressionists and was, in turn, influenced by them. In the 1860s, the Impressionists began meeting near Manet’s studio at Café Guerbois. He was the unofficial head of the twice-weekly meetings, which included Monet, Renoir, Degas, Alfred Sisley, Émile Zola, and sometimes Paul Cézanne, Camille Pissarro, and others. \n\nWhat was the bridge between Realism and Impressionism? It was Manet’s new approach to painting, his innovations with color and brushwork. \n\nEarlier artists began painting their canvases with a layer of dark, usually brown, paint and then built layers of paint on top of it. Of course, they had to wait for each layer to dry before adding the next one. Finally, they glazed the painting to give the surface a smooth finish. This process could take weeks or months. Obviously, the models couldn’t pose all that time, so painters frequently added layers without the model present.\n\nAs a Realist, Manet preferred to paint from life — in other words, with his model in front of him. He did this by completing his paintings in one sitting. How did he achieve this high-speed efficiency? By not painting in layers and not glazing the final product. That meant he had to choose the perfect color right off the bat because there were no layers to fall back on. When he made a mistake, he scraped off the paint, down to the bare canvas, and then repainted that area.",
      "questionNumber": 30,
      "questionText": "The process of layering and glazing paintings could take months?",
      "answer": "True",
      "option1": "True",
      "option2": "False",
      "option3": "",
      "option4": ""
    },
    {
      "resource": "The classically trained Édouard Manet (1832–1883) straddled Realism and Impressionism. He influenced the Impressionists and was, in turn, influenced by them. In the 1860s, the Impressionists began meeting near Manet’s studio at Café Guerbois. He was the unofficial head of the twice-weekly meetings, which included Monet, Renoir, Degas, Alfred Sisley, Émile Zola, and sometimes Paul Cézanne, Camille Pissarro, and others. \n\nWhat was the bridge between Realism and Impressionism? It was Manet’s new approach to painting, his innovations with color and brushwork. \n\nEarlier artists began painting their canvases with a layer of dark, usually brown, paint and then built layers of paint on top of it. Of course, they had to wait for each layer to dry before adding the next one. Finally, they glazed the painting to give the surface a smooth finish. This process could take weeks or months. Obviously, the models couldn’t pose all that time, so painters frequently added layers without the model present.\n\nAs a Realist, Manet preferred to paint from life — in other words, with his model in front of him. He did this by completing his paintings in one sitting. How did he achieve this high-speed efficiency? By not painting in layers and not glazing the final product. That meant he had to choose the perfect color right off the bat because there were no layers to fall back on. When he made a mistake, he scraped off the paint, down to the bare canvas, and then repainted that area.",
      "questionNumber": 31,
      "questionText": "Manet was the unofficial head of fortnightly meetings between painters?",
      "answer": "False",
      "option1": "True",
      "option2": "False",
      "option3": "",
      "option4": ""
    },
    {
      "resource": "The classically trained Édouard Manet (1832–1883) straddled Realism and Impressionism. He influenced the Impressionists and was, in turn, influenced by them. In the 1860s, the Impressionists began meeting near Manet’s studio at Café Guerbois. He was the unofficial head of the twice-weekly meetings, which included Monet, Renoir, Degas, Alfred Sisley, Émile Zola, and sometimes Paul Cézanne, Camille Pissarro, and others. \n\nWhat was the bridge between Realism and Impressionism? It was Manet’s new approach to painting, his innovations with color and brushwork. \n\nEarlier artists began painting their canvases with a layer of dark, usually brown, paint and then built layers of paint on top of it. Of course, they had to wait for each layer to dry before adding the next one. Finally, they glazed the painting to give the surface a smooth finish. This process could take weeks or months. Obviously, the models couldn’t pose all that time, so painters frequently added layers without the model present.\n\nAs a Realist, Manet preferred to paint from life — in other words, with his model in front of him. He did this by completing his paintings in one sitting. How did he achieve this high-speed efficiency? By not painting in layers and not glazing the final product. That meant he had to choose the perfect color right off the bat because there were no layers to fall back on. When he made a mistake, he scraped off the paint, down to the bare canvas, and then repainted that area.",
      "questionNumber": 32,
      "questionText": "The layers of paint used by earlier artists tended to be brown?",
      "answer": "False",
      "option1": "True",
      "option2": "False",
      "option3": "",
      "option4": ""
    },
    {
      "resource": "Space is yet another factor to consider when growing plants. Both the roots and foliage (leaves) need room to grow. Without enough room, plants can become stunted or too small. Overcrowded plants are also more likely to suffer from diseases since airflow may be limited.\n\nPenultimately, plants require time. They do not grow overnight. It takes time and patience to grow plants, some more so than others. Most plants require a particular number of days, months, or even years to produce flowers and fruit.",
      "questionNumber": 33,
      "questionText": "What is one of the disadvantages of growing plants in small pots?",
      "answer": "The plants may not grow to their full potential",
      "option1": "The plants may suffer from disease",
      "option2": "The plants may not grow to their full potential",
      "option3": "The plants may not access the correct amount of nutrients",
      "option4": "The plants may not access the correct amount of air"
    },
    {
      "resource": "Space is yet another factor to consider when growing plants. Both the roots and foliage (leaves) need room to grow. Without enough room, plants can become stunted or too small. Overcrowded plants are also more likely to suffer from diseases since airflow may be limited.\n\nPenultimately, plants require time. They do not grow overnight. It takes time and patience to grow plants, some more so than others. Most plants require a particular number of days, months, or even years to produce flowers and fruit.",
      "questionNumber": 34,
      "questionText": "From the text one can infer that:",
      "answer": "Someone who is impatient may struggle with growing plants",
      "option1": "Overcrowded plants are less likely to grow",
      "option2": "It is impossible for the plant to grow if either the roots or the foliage has no space to grow",
      "option3": "Someone who is impatient may struggle with growing plants",
      "option4": "A single type of plant can take a different amount of time to grow"
    },
    {
      "resource": "Space is yet another factor to consider when growing plants. Both the roots and foliage (leaves) need room to grow. Without enough room, plants can become stunted or too small. Overcrowded plants are also more likely to suffer from diseases since airflow may be limited.\n\nPenultimately, plants require time. They do not grow overnight. It takes time and patience to grow plants, some more so than others. Most plants require a particular number of days, months, or even years to produce flowers and fruit.",
      "questionNumber": 35,
      "questionText": "Where in the full body of text can you expect this extract:",
      "answer": "False",
      "option1": "Opening paragraphs",
      "option2": "Concluding paragraph",
      "option3": "Towards the end",
      "option4": "Towards the middle"
    },
    {
      "resource": "Space is yet another factor to consider when growing plants. Both the roots and foliage (leaves) need room to grow. Without enough room, plants can become stunted or too small. Overcrowded plants are also more likely to suffer from diseases since airflow may be limited.\n\nPenultimately, plants require time. They do not grow overnight. It takes time and patience to grow plants, some more so than others. Most plants require a particular number of days, months, or even years to produce flowers and fruit.",
      "questionNumber": 36,
      "questionText": "The text states that:",
      "answer": "Overcrowded plants are more likely to contract disease",
      "option1": "Overcrowded plants are more likely to contract disease",
      "option2": "Plants without leaves are likely to do better without space",
      "option3": "Space is crucial the growth of plants",
      "option4": "All plants need time to grow"
    },
    {
      "resource": "The Ottoman empire was centered in present-day Turkey, and extended its influence into southeastern Europe as well as the Middle East. Europe was only temporarily able to resist their advance: the turning point came at the Battle of Varna in 1444 when a European coalition army failed to stop the Turkish advance. Only Constantinople (Istanbul) remained in Byzantine hands and its conquest in 1453 seemed inevitable after Varna. The Turks subsequently established an empire in Anatolia and southeastern Europe which lasted until the early twentieth century.\n\nAlthough the Ottoman Empire is not considered a European kingdom per se, Ottoman expansion had a profound impact on a continent already stunned by the calamities of the fourteenth and fifteenth centuries and the Ottoman Turks must, therefore, be considered in any study of Europe in the late Middle Ages. The ease with which the Ottoman Empire achieved military victories led Western Europeans to fear that ongoing Ottoman success would collapse the political and social infrastructure of the West and bring about the downfall of Christendom. Such a momentous threat could not be ignored and the Europeans mounted crusades against the Ottomans in 1366, 1396, and 1444, but to no avail. The Ottomans continued to conquer new territories.",
      "questionNumber": 37,
      "questionText": "The empire had established a foothold in Europe for roughly:",
      "answer": "500 years",
      "option1": "400 years",
      "option2": "500 years",
      "option3": "600 years",
      "option4": "300 years"
    },
    {
      "resource": "The Ottoman empire was centered in present-day Turkey, and extended its influence into southeastern Europe as well as the Middle East. Europe was only temporarily able to resist their advance: the turning point came at the Battle of Varna in 1444 when a European coalition army failed to stop the Turkish advance. Only Constantinople (Istanbul) remained in Byzantine hands and its conquest in 1453 seemed inevitable after Varna. The Turks subsequently established an empire in Anatolia and southeastern Europe which lasted until the early twentieth century.\n\nAlthough the Ottoman Empire is not considered a European kingdom per se, Ottoman expansion had a profound impact on a continent already stunned by the calamities of the fourteenth and fifteenth centuries and the Ottoman Turks must, therefore, be considered in any study of Europe in the late Middle Ages. The ease with which the Ottoman Empire achieved military victories led Western Europeans to fear that ongoing Ottoman success would collapse the political and social infrastructure of the West and bring about the downfall of Christendom. Such a momentous threat could not be ignored and the Europeans mounted crusades against the Ottomans in 1366, 1396, and 1444, but to no avail. The Ottomans continued to conquer new territories.",
      "questionNumber": 38,
      "questionText": "According to the text, The battle of Varna was:",
      "answer": "Years before the invasion of Constantinople",
      "option1": "The invasion of Constantinople",
      "option2": "Years before the invasion of Constantinople",
      "option3": "A crusade",
      "option4": "Took place in 1444 and ended in 1453"
    },
    {
      "resource": "The Ottoman empire was centered in present-day Turkey, and extended its influence into southeastern Europe as well as the Middle East. Europe was only temporarily able to resist their advance: the turning point came at the Battle of Varna in 1444 when a European coalition army failed to stop the Turkish advance. Only Constantinople (Istanbul) remained in Byzantine hands and its conquest in 1453 seemed inevitable after Varna. The Turks subsequently established an empire in Anatolia and southeastern Europe which lasted until the early twentieth century.\n\nAlthough the Ottoman Empire is not considered a European kingdom per se, Ottoman expansion had a profound impact on a continent already stunned by the calamities of the fourteenth and fifteenth centuries and the Ottoman Turks must, therefore, be considered in any study of Europe in the late Middle Ages. The ease with which the Ottoman Empire achieved military victories led Western Europeans to fear that ongoing Ottoman success would collapse the political and social infrastructure of the West and bring about the downfall of Christendom. Such a momentous threat could not be ignored and the Europeans mounted crusades against the Ottomans in 1366, 1396, and 1444, but to no avail. The Ottomans continued to conquer new territories.",
      "questionNumber": 39,
      "questionText": "The empire achieved victories so easily that:",
      "answer": "Europeans believed it would lead to the fall of Christendom",
      "option1": "Europeans worried that it would lead to global domination",
      "option2": "They should be considered in any study of European middle ages",
      "option3": "Europeans mounted several crusades against them",
      "option4": "Europeans believed it would lead to the fall of Christendom"
    },
    {
      "resource": "The Ottoman empire was centered in present-day Turkey, and extended its influence into southeastern Europe as well as the Middle East. Europe was only temporarily able to resist their advance: the turning point came at the Battle of Varna in 1444 when a European coalition army failed to stop the Turkish advance. Only Constantinople (Istanbul) remained in Byzantine hands and its conquest in 1453 seemed inevitable after Varna. The Turks subsequently established an empire in Anatolia and southeastern Europe which lasted until the early twentieth century.\n\nAlthough the Ottoman Empire is not considered a European kingdom per se, Ottoman expansion had a profound impact on a continent already stunned by the calamities of the fourteenth and fifteenth centuries and the Ottoman Turks must, therefore, be considered in any study of Europe in the late Middle Ages. The ease with which the Ottoman Empire achieved military victories led Western Europeans to fear that ongoing Ottoman success would collapse the political and social infrastructure of the West and bring about the downfall of Christendom. Such a momentous threat could not be ignored and the Europeans mounted crusades against the Ottomans in 1366, 1396, and 1444, but to no avail. The Ottomans continued to conquer new territories.",
      "questionNumber": 40,
      "questionText": "The final battle which the text references Europeans fighting against the Ottoman empire",
      "answer": "1444",
      "option1": "1396",
      "option2": "1366",
      "option3": "1444",
      "option4": "1453"
    },
    {
      "resource": "In the 1600s, an English physicist and mathematician named Isaac Newton was sitting under an apple tree -- or so the legend tells us. Apparently, an apple fell on his head, and he started wondering why the apple was attracted to the ground in the first place.\n\nNewton publicized his Theory of Universal Gravitation in the 1680s. It basically set forth the idea that gravity was a predictable force that acts on all matter in the universe, and is a function of both mass and distance. The theory states that each particle of matter attracts every other particle (for instance, the particles of 'Earth' and the particles of 'you') with a force that is directly proportional to the product of their masses and inversely proportional to the square of the distance between them. The force of gravity acting on an object is also that object's weight. When you step on a scale, the scale reads how much gravity is acting on your body. ",
      "questionNumber": 41,
      "questionText": "Newton publicised his Theory of Universal Gravitation: ",
      "answer": "20 years before the 18th century",
      "option1": "During the period of Enlightnement",
      "option2": "20 years before the 18th century",
      "option3": "During the 16th century",
      "option4": "At the age of 80"
    },
    {
      "resource": "In the 1600s, an English physicist and mathematician named Isaac Newton was sitting under an apple tree -- or so the legend tells us. Apparently, an apple fell on his head, and he started wondering why the apple was attracted to the ground in the first place.\n\nNewton publicized his Theory of Universal Gravitation in the 1680s. It basically set forth the idea that gravity was a predictable force that acts on all matter in the universe, and is a function of both mass and distance. The theory states that each particle of matter attracts every other particle (for instance, the particles of 'Earth' and the particles of 'you') with a force that is directly proportional to the product of their masses and inversely proportional to the square of the distance between them. The force of gravity acting on an object is also that object's weight. When you step on a scale, the scale reads how much gravity is acting on your body. ",
      "questionNumber": 42,
      "questionText": "According to the text, when you step on a scale:",
      "answer": "When you step on a scale, your particles attract the particles of the scale",
      "option1": "When you step on a scale, your particles attract the particles of the scale",
      "option2": "The force of gravity acts on you",
      "option3": "The scale reads how much gravity is pulling you down",
      "option4": "The scale reads your weight"
    },
    {
      "resource": "In the 1600s, an English physicist and mathematician named Isaac Newton was sitting under an apple tree -- or so the legend tells us. Apparently, an apple fell on his head, and he started wondering why the apple was attracted to the ground in the first place.\n\nNewton publicized his Theory of Universal Gravitation in the 1680s. It basically set forth the idea that gravity was a predictable force that acts on all matter in the universe, and is a function of both mass and distance. The theory states that each particle of matter attracts every other particle (for instance, the particles of 'Earth' and the particles of 'you') with a force that is directly proportional to the product of their masses and inversely proportional to the square of the distance between them. The force of gravity acting on an object is also that object's weight. When you step on a scale, the scale reads how much gravity is acting on your body. ",
      "questionNumber": 43,
      "questionText": "According to Newton:",
      "answer": "Gravity is a function of both mass and distance",
      "option1": "Gravity is an unpredictable force that varies depending on where you are in the universe",
      "option2": "Gravity caused the apple to fall on his head",
      "option3": "The amount of gravity acting on an object is also the mass of the object",
      "option4": "Gravity is a function of both mass and distance"
    },
    {
      "resource": "In the 1600s, an English physicist and mathematician named Isaac Newton was sitting under an apple tree -- or so the legend tells us. Apparently, an apple fell on his head, and he started wondering why the apple was attracted to the ground in the first place.\n\nNewton publicized his Theory of Universal Gravitation in the 1680s. It basically set forth the idea that gravity was a predictable force that acts on all matter in the universe, and is a function of both mass and distance. The theory states that each particle of matter attracts every other particle (for instance, the particles of 'Earth' and the particles of 'you') with a force that is directly proportional to the product of their masses and inversely proportional to the square of the distance between them. The force of gravity acting on an object is also that object's weight. When you step on a scale, the scale reads how much gravity is acting on your body. ",
      "questionNumber": 44,
      "questionText": "‘Or so the legend tells us’ means:",
      "answer": "It is a famous story",
      "option1": "It is highly likely that this is true",
      "option2": "It is highly unlikely that this is true",
      "option3": "It is a famous story",
      "option4": "The author doesn’t believe this story"
    }
  ]
}
